



### **AKSHAT PURI**

### **PROFILE**

I'm a skilled game programmer with three years of experience. I enjoy collaborating with teams to create captivating and seamless gaming experiences. In my free time, you can catch me gaming, staying up-to-date with the latest industry trends, or tinkering with new game engine technologies.

#### SKILLS

- Languages- C, C++, C#, Java, GDscript
- Graphic Libraries-SFML, STL, OpenGL
- Source Control- Git, Plastic, Beyond Compare
- Game Engine -Unity3D, Godot
- Art- Photoshop

# EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

BS HONS IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND GAME DEVELOPMENT

Backstage Pass Institute of Gaming and Technology, Hyderabad 2019-2022

12th (CBSC) Delhi Public School, Varanasi 2017 - 2019 10th (ICSC) St johns DLW, Varanasi, 2016-2017

### WORK EXPERIENCE

### Xigma Games | Game Programmer (2022-Present)

Currently working on upcoming release **Metal haven** an action strategy game set in Sci-Fi-world with different planets.

- Ported Bonfire Forsaken land (first title- 2D Strategy game) single handedly to Xbox and Nintendo switch consoles in Unity.
- Made a tool for the smooth transition from FMOD to Unity's built-in audio engine for Xbox One
- Programmed editor tools and map generation tools to be used by a team of 7
- · Worked on AI using behavior trees and flow field for the squad system
- Helped the team to achieve smooth dynamic map integrations <u>LINK</u>

## Tentaxaur Studios | Lead Programmer (March 2021 - June 2021)

Managed a team of 3 to create hypercasual mobile games in Unity

- Created the entire gameplay, UI and level progression for finger smashing game
- · Integrated various SDK -Admob, IAP, Analytics, Google Play services
- Helped uploading on mobile platforms -Android | IOS <u>LINK</u>

### Freelance Developer (2022- Present)

Paid work for clients, both individuals and indie studios Completed various game programming project on contract basis

### PERSONAL PROJECTS

### Can you do it? | BYOG Game Jam 2022 Honorable Mention Programmer and Level Designer 2022

2d platformer with mirror dimensions and mind bending puzzles.

- Collaborated in a team of 3 for this project.
- Designed five unique levels with mind puzzles in UNITY.
- Programmed 2d platformer with mirrored platforming. LINK

### Scream way up! | Developer (2021)

Arcade game where you use your voice to play or scream

- Made physics engine from scratch in Unity3D
- Added Microphone support
- Added Ads, IAP SDK's
- Designed Unlockable content like characters and Artwork in photoshop LINK

### Black Game engine | Programmer and Designer (WIP)

Developing a game engine in my part time for personal projects

- Implemented OPENGL API for rendering
- future plans to integrate BOX2D for physics
- PBR and editor support LINK